# Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

# Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

Æ	Kadıköy, İstanbul (Asia) - Turkey
2	+90 (542) 5362620
$\boxtimes$	kenanb@6x13.com
$\boxtimes$	kenanbolukbasi@gmail.com
£	☑ kenanb.com ☑ 6x13.com
•	🗷 blendernetwork.org/kenan-bolukbasi
<b>≝</b>	♥ kenanbolukbasi 🔊 blog.6x13.com
	• kenanb • 6x13

# SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

## PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP Turkish, Bulgarian DRIVER'S LICENCE **B** Class

DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH 28th January 1987, Bulgaria

# **EDUCATION**

2005 - 2017Architecture (B.Arch.) Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul 2001 - 2005High School (Science and Math) Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School, Bursa

# Conferences & Workshops

## TALKS GIVEN

2016	Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul	
2014	<b>Prototyping &amp; Optimizing Game Asset Workflow</b> Blender Conference, Amsterdam	
2014	Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig	
2014	<b>Blender Python Programming Workshop</b> BlendFX Studios, Leipzig	
2011	AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul	

# P

Participation		
2015	Game Developers Conference EU 2015 (Cologne) UBM Tech	
2014	Blender Conference (Amsterdam) Blender Foundation	
2014	Libre Graphics Meeting (Leipzig)  LGM Crew	
2014	<b>Blender Python Workshop (Leipzig)</b> Kenan Bölükbaşı	
2011	<b>IAF Compositing Workshop (İstanbul)</b> Özgür Gülbir	

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# 6x13 Games, İstanbul

## JAN 2015 - [ CONT'D ]

# Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design & development. Graphics design and game asset creation. Prototyping & workflow optimization.

- Game design, artwork and development of WreckJumper (WIP), a forced-perspective top-down turn-based strategy game with dynamic puzzle elements in a sci-fi theme.
- Game design, development, project management, graphics & user interface design of Twiniwt, the globally featured symmetrical movement puzzle.
- Project lead and development of 1FPS Game Series.
- Development of a Cocos2d-x based generic infrastructure to use for cross-platform mobile projects.
- · Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project at ITU. It aims to develop facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Guest speaker at several Architectural Design Computing Master's Program classes at ITU.

#### EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL Aug 2013 - Jan 2015 Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- Development of an asset workflow & automation system (capable of lighting, rendering, compositing and atlas generation) for a mobile real-time strategy game project.
- Environment art and map editor development for a tower defense game.
- Prototyping and automation of pseudo-3D asset generation for a football game.

# FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

JUN 2011 - FEB 2014

## Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

#### EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 - SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Managing the construction site of a large steel structure for the wedding event of daughter of İlham Aliyev, the President of Azerbaijan, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish and Azerbaijani) environment.

# SOSYALMEDYA.CO, İSTANBUL

FEB 2011 - MAR 2012

# Author

Tech industry-specific reports and news. Opinion pieces in monthly electronical journal. An interview with Mustafa İçil, former Turkey & MEA Regional Marketing Manager of Google.

# EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL Event Supervisor

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Designing event visuals, workflow and stageflow management. Events include: Microsoft Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, trip to the Czech Republic as part of VIP event. Customers include: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş Holding, Soyak.

# Aşçıoğlu İnşaat, İstanbul

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

# Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

# ALPO Engineering, İstanbul

Mar 2007 - May 2007

## 3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

## PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

#### PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

## 2017 Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured in the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories as well as the AppStore Turkey homepage. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

# 2016 **1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games**

3 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

## 2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games

An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

## 2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

## 2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation work-flow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

# 2013 **Hy Programming Language Blender Integration**Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support

## 2012 **CL-IES**

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

#### 2011 TwitGraph

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

### DESIGN PROJECTS

- 2016 **ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project**Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- 2014 **StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos**Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest.
  Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Çankaya Ulvi Cemal Erkin Concert Hall & Cultural Center Architectural Design Competition Participation (with Gülsev Özbelen & Gizem Kaya)
- 2010 **Nooka International Watch Design Competition**Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design
- 2009 **Akçansa Concrete Ideas Competition**Finalist (with Büşra Atabek)

# COMMUNICATION SKILLS

## ENGLISH

Listening: C2 (Mastery)\*
 Reading: C2 (Mastery)\*

Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)\*
 Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)\*

• Writing: C2 (Mastery)\*

- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing – ITU Research Paper Writing – ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties. Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP customers including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

#### AZERBAIJANI

- Listening: B2 (Upper intermediate)\* Reading: B1 (Intermediate)\*
- A2 (Elementary)\*
- A1 (Beginner)\*
- Work experience for a month in Baku.
   Several organizations with Azerbaijani customers.

## TURKISH

- · Native Speaker
- (\*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

# SOFTWARE SKILLS

#### GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

Blender 3D
Inkscape

ImageMagick, FFMpeg

GIMP, Photoshop
3D Studio Max, Maya

BI & Cycles Renderers

Luxrender, Yafaray

AutoCAD, DraftSight
Luminance HDR

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

**C / C++** 

Common Lisp, Scheme

Python, Factor

UNIX / Shell

■■■ Lua, HTML5

# DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

**Emacs** 

**■■■■** Visual Studio

GCC, Clang, MSBuild

GDB, LLDB, Valgrind

■■■ Make, CMake, Gradle

Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++)

Git Version Control System

Xcode, Android Studio

## OPERATING SYSTEMS

GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian)
Windows XP/7/8/10

macOS

# DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

T<sub>E</sub>X / L<sup>e</sup>T<sub>E</sub>X Systems

Org-Mode, Markdown

Doxygen, Pandoc

MS Office, Libre Office, Scribus

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

HOBBIES Walking, Computer Science, Technology

Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing

COMMUNITIES Free / Libre & Open Source Software,

Blender Network, Lisp Game Development,

Factor Language Development